It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Musashi had a match against Baiken, the user of kusarigama, during the trip to Edotopia.
에도토피아를 향한 여행을 계속하는 무사시는 쿠사리가마를 사용하는 바이켄과 만나 대전했다.
In front of the might of kusarigama that he saw for the first time, Musashi was flustered and had a hard fight.
처음 보는 쿠사리가마의 위력의 대단함에 한결같던 무사시도 쩔쩔, 고전을 면치 못한다.
But after all, a new friendship has born. Musashi has promised to meet him again in the martial arts competition, and left.
그러나 우정이 트었다. 그리고 에도토피아의 무예 대회에서 재회를 단단히 약속하고 떠났다.
Evil Hanzō Creeps
악의 한조, 살며시 다가오오
Thank you for waiting, Lord Hanzō.
한조 님, 기다리셨습니다.
Right. I appreciate you for greeting me, Zenzō.
그래, 마중 수고했다, 젠조.
Hanzō
한조
Now, where is the thing?
그럼, 예의 물건은?
Yes, it is inside here.
예, 이 안에 있습니다.
This is it.
이것입니다.
I see. Those are fine gold.
그렇군. 훌륭한 금이다.
Do not let any information about this place leak.
어떻게 해서라도 밖으로 알려지지 않게 해라.
Got it.
예.
With this, the world is in my hands.
이것만 있으면 천하는 나, 한조의 것.
Meanwhile, having Kojirō in mind, Musashi was heading to Edotopia, carrying Kotetsu, his beloved swords, on his waist.
그 쯤 무사시는 코지로를 마음에 두고 있으면서도, 애도 코테츠를 허리에 차고 쭉 에도토피아를 향해 가고 있었다.
That must be Kojirō!
저건 코지로!
Wait-dasu!
기다리시오!
Do you have anything to say to me?
뭔가 소생에게 볼 일이?
No, no, uh, that is, I was looking for a different person-dasu. Excuse me-dasu.
아니, 아니, 그게, 다른 사람이었소. 실례했소.
What's up with this guy?
뭐야, 얘?
Is it Zenzō?
젠조인가.
-Yes. -Speak.
-예. -말해라.
A few days ago, it is told that Jūbee, the police chief, stopped by at Hōzōin Dōjō.
며칠 전, 호조인 도장에 경찰 장관 주베가 나타났다 합니다.
Jūbee? That bastard... He is not supposed to be a spy investigating across the state.
주베가? 그 놈... 제국의 동세를 정탐하는 역이 아닐 터.
How dare he tries to take over my role?
내탐꾼인 내 임무에 감히 손을 대다니.
But it is possible that Jūbee appeared in that place because of the gold mine...
그러나 이런 때, 그런 곳에 주베가 나타났다는 것은 설마 그 금광...
Don't be flustered. There is no mistake. And for you...
당황하지 마라. 실수는 없다. 그쪽은...
Who is there?!
누구냐!
Spies! Get them!
수상한 놈이다! 잡아라!
We're going to be caught like this. Run away by yourself!
이대로는 함께 잡힌다. 너라도 달아나라!
I shall not! Why would you say that?
그럴 수는 없다! 뭔 생각인가?
If we get caught together, who will expose Hanzō's plot?
우리가 함께 잡히면 한조의 음모를 누가...
Take this to Jūbee right away!
자. 빨리 이걸 주베 님께!
Something's over there!
뭔가 있다!
You go look that way! I'll check over that side.
넌 그쪽을 찾아봐라! 난 저 넘어를 보겠다.
Forget about me. Hurry!
내겐 신경쓰지 마라. 서둘러라!
Found him!
찾았다!
Appreciated.
미안하다.
Freeze!
멈춰라!
Meanwhile, Kojirō was heading to Edotopia, and Musashi was nowhere to be found in his thoughts.
그 쯤 코지로는 무사시를 전혀 신경쓰지 않고 쭉 에도토피아를 향하고 있었다.
What happened? Wake up!
무슨 일인가, 대체?! 정신 차려라!
Bring this to Jūbee...
주, 주베 님께...
Hey! Are you alright? Hey!
어이! 괜찮나! 어이!
Pigeons?
비둘기?
To Jūbee?
주베에게?
What are you all talking about-dasu?
뭘 가지고 웅성대오?
Is it dead?
죽은 걸까...
It's not moving.
안 움직이네.
-A pigeon! -Yeah, it was under that tree injured.
-비둘기! -응, 상처를 입고 저 나무 아래에 떨어져 있었어.
Injured? We must help that pitiful thing in that case-dasu.
상처를? 그럼 빨리 돕지 않으면 불쌍하오.
dasu, you say?
하오?
Even if you say so, we can't do anything about a karakuri bird.
그런 말을 해도 우리는 카라쿠리 새는 어떻게 못 해.
You can leave that to me-dasu!
아, 그런 거라면 내게 맡기시오!
How much are you going to pay us-dasu?
얼마 줄 것이오?
How much? Didn't you say you picked this up-dasu?
얼마라니, 주운 거 아니오?
Oh, I get it! Then let's go throw it away at somewhere else!
아, 그래라! 그럼 어딘가에 버리러 가자!
So stingy!
쩨쩨하긴!
-Let's go. -Hey, stop-dasu!
-가자. -아, 멈추시오!
Man, kids nowadays are so sneaky-dasu...
거참, 최근 아이들은 방심할 수가 없소...
Here! Are you satisfied-dasu?
자! 이 정도면 만족하오?
-You bought it-dasu! -dasu!
-이제 산 것이오! -이오!
Man.
이것 참...
Anyway, let me take a look-dasu.
자, 어쨌든 한번 보겠소.
That's a big wound-dasu.
와, 대단한 상처이오...
Huh?
어?
What is this-dasu?
뭣이오, 이것은?
What-dasu?!
뭐요!
How cowardly-dasu!
참 비겁하오!
What do you have against me-dasu?!
내게 무슨 원한이 있는 것이오!
I'll come back later to treat you, so stay here-dasu!
나중에 꼭 치료해 줄 테니까 여기 있소!
Damn, what's going on-dasu?!
젠장, 뭔 일이오!
Who are you-dasu?! Why are you after me-dasu?!
누구시오! 왜 날 노리시오!
Why are ninjas chasing Musashi?
무사시가 왜 닌자들에게...
There's no way that Musashi killed that other ninja just before.
설마 조금 전 닌자를 무사시가 죽였을 리도 없고.
What swift rat!
발 빠른 놈!
Do not let him get away! Catch him!
잡아라! 쫒아!
What persistent bastards-dasu...
끈질긴 놈들이오...
What did I wrong to get in this situation-dasu...
어째 내가 이런 상황에 처하게 됐소...
Are they possibly looking for this...?
놈들, 설마 이걸...?
It seems that Musashi has managed to get away from pursuers.
무사시 놈, 어떻게든 추격자를 따돌린 모양이구나.
But yet...
그래도...
Right, you're going to be fine-dasu.
좋소, 이제 괜찮을 것이오.
You'll be able to fly again-dasu!
다시 날 수 있게 될 것이오!
Maybe I should better return this-dasu.
역시 이것도 돌려주는 게 좋겠소...
Wait!
잠깐!
Yo- you are!
너, 너는!
Kojirō!
코지로!
What are you doing-dasu?!
뭔 짓이오!
It seems that the owner of this dove and the dead are somehow related.
이 비둘기의 주인하고 죽은 자하고 상관있는 듯 하구나.
Anyway, this seems to be has something to do with Jūbee.
어쨌든 이것이 주베와 관계가 있을 듯 하다.
With Jūbee?
주베 씨하고?
This...
이건...
Possibly, a code of something.
어쩌면 무언가의 부호.
Or a secret message using steganography.
아니, 글자를 숨긴 밀서일지도.
A secret message-dasu?
밀서이오?
Right. We should know the reason you were chased by reading this.
그렇다. 읽어보면 네가 몹시 노려진 이유도 알게 될 것이다.
Look at this!
어라, 이것은!
It's a character-dasu!
글자이오!
What's going on here?!
이, 이건 대체!
So I see how this device works.
그렇군, 이런 장치였군!
It's pretty well done. The characters written inside are getting projected.
꽤 잘 되어 있다. 비치는 것은 여기에 적혀 있던 글자다.
I can't read for some reason-dasu...
왠지 읽혀지지 않소...
I will read.
내가 읽겠다.
This is an application of the mechanism behind a pinhole camera.
이것은 바늘구멍 사진기를 응용한 것이다.
It's as if an ancestor of the modern cameras, using a small hole instead of a lens.
핀홀 카메라라고 불려, 렌즈 대신 작은 구멍을 이용한, 말하자면 카메라의 고선조격이다.
"Hanzō, a villain with two faces, shall be exposed here."
"두 개의 얼굴을 가진 악당, 한조의 정체를 여기에 적는다."
Hanzō? Who is it?
한조? 누구이오?
Not that I know well, but I heard that he is the head of the Iga ninjas, working as an official spy under General Ieyasu.
나도 잘은 모르지만 이하(伊賀) 닌자의 수장으로써 제너럴 이에야스 막부의 밀정이라고 들었다.
Then was that spy chasing me-dasu?
그럼 날 쫒은 건 그 밀정이오?
No. I don't think so. Take a look for yourself.
아니. 아닌 것 같다. 한번 봐라.
"This man is a general who maintains public peace and order as an official spy,"
"이 남자, 막부의 밀정으로써 지팡구국의 치안을 지키는 장군이면서 실은 뒤에서 다이묘 간 싸움을 붙여"
"continuing his practice of stirring up trouble."
"이 세상의 치안을 어지럽히는 일을 이어왔습니다."
"Moreover, owning many gold mines across the state without reporting can only mean to overthrow the shōgunate."
"게다가 이만큼이나 막부에 신고하지 않고 각지의 금광을 소유하는 것은 분명히 막부를 전복시키려는 것."
"It is the proof that he is scheming to reign over Jipangu State as the shadow shōgun."
"자신이 지팡구국의 막후 조종자로써 군림하고자 한다는 증거입니다."
"Following is the location of gold mine. Waiting for the decision from Jūbee."
"다음은 금광의 위치입니다. 주베 님의 결단을 바랍니다."
That's one unforgivable guy-dasu...
용서 못 할 놈이오...
Hanzō's evil hands are approaching. Wait for the stormy latter half!
한조의 마의 손이 다가온다. 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
While I got the situation, I do not want to be involved.
사정을 알았지만 말려들고 싶지는 않다.
What are you saying-dasu?
무슨 말이오?
Didn't you get it, Musashi?!
알아채지 못했나, 무사시!
Kojirō!
코지로!
Do not spend your life for nothing! See you again!
생명을 소홀히 여기지 마라! 다시 만나자!
Wait for me, Kojirō!
기다리시오, 코지로!
Do not follow me! Divide up to two and escape this situation! Change your path!
따라오지 마라! 둘로 나뉘어 위기를 모면해라! 다른 길로 돌아가라!
Whatever you say, I cannot run away by myself-dasu!
그런 말을 해도 혼자 달아날 수는 없소!
Then I'll go that way instead!
그럼 내가 건너로 가겠다!
Wait for me-dasu!
기다리시오!
Wh- what the-?!
뭣이오?
We have nothing to do with that. Move away!
우리하고는 어떤 관계도 없다. 비켜라!
What the-?!
뭐요?
I won't fall for that-dasu!
이런 것에는 당하지 않소!
Oh no-dasu!
아뿔싸이오!
Dammit! Cook, throw into a fire, or do whatever you want-dasu!
젠장! 이렇게 됐다면 익히든 태우든 원하는 대로 하시오!
He already gave up. What simpleton he is!
벌써 저런다. 왜 녀석은 단세포인 거냐!
That's as far as you go!
거기까지다!
Put down the sword! Or he's as good as dead!
칼을 내려놓아라! 안 놓으면 생명은 없다!
Okay, I wouldn't like if they do whatever they want-dasu!
역시 원하는 대로 하는 건 싫소!
I have nothing to do with this!
나하고는 상관없는 일이다!
First, that guy does not have anything. Even if you kill, you won't get a thing!
일단, 이 녀석은 무엇도 가지고 있지 않다. 죽여봤자 소용없다!
How irresponsible he is!
무, 무슨 무책임한 소리를!
Well, you might understand if you investigate as much as you want.
뭐, 너희들 직성 풀릴 때까지 알아보면 알게 되겠지.
Stop right there! You shall not run away!
멈춰라! 달아나는가!
Wh- what the...
이, 이건!
Damn... Kojirō ran away-dasu!
젠장, 코지로 놈, 달아났소!
It's no use. Retreating for now.
어쩔 수 없지. 어쨌든 퇴각이다.
At least we'd be able to find something out from this guy. We'll find out in plenty.
이 녀석이라도 있으면 어떻게든 되겠지. 충분히 알아볼 테니까.
Hey! Untie me!
이거 놓으시오!
What a lively boy.
활기찬 사내자식이군.
You!
너는!
Head of Iga Ninja Force, Hanzō! But first, would you be okay to act violently, you brat?
이하 닌자 군단 수장, 한조! 그보다도 그렇게 날뛰어도 괜찮을까, 꼬맹아.
There are mines under your feet. If you lose balance, you'll fall right away.
네 발 아래에는 지뢰가 깔려 있다. 균형을 잃으면 바로 떨어지겠지.
Now! Tell me where the secret message is!
자! 밀서는 어디 있나!
I don't have any secret message-dasu!
난 밀서 따위 가지고 있지 않소!
But it wasn't in the pigeon. Where did you hide the message at?
하지만 비둘기에는 없었다. 어디에 숨겼나!
I don't know what I don't know-dasu!
모르는 것은 모르는 것이오!
Alright then. Let's see when your stubbornness goes away.
좋다. 어디까지 그 고집이 갈지 보여줘 보아라.
-Even if you do not fall, that device will follow law of nature. -You're cowardly-dasu! I know nothing-dasu!
-네가 안 떨어져도 그 장치는 자연을 따른다. -비겁하오! 난 아무것도 모르오!
If you want to live, you shall reveal the location you hid the message.
살고 싶다면 그 전에 숨긴 곳을 밝혀라.
If you keep doing this, you won't be able to find the secret message-dasu!
그런 걸 하면 밀서는 찾을 수 없소!
It doesn't matter. There is another living witness.
상관없다. 산 증인은 하나 더 있으니까.
Now, let us wait with leisure meanwhile.
자. 그 동안 한가로이 기다리고나 있을까.
-Keep an eye on him. -Help me-dasu!
-잘 보고 있어라. -살려주시오!
Help me-dasu!
살려주시오!
Why must I be in this situation-dasu?!
왜 내가 이런 꼴에 처해야 하오!
That's it! Kojirō!
그래! 코지로다!
That's it-dasu! It's all because Kojirō ran away!
그렇소! 코지로가 달아난 탓이오!
Kojirō's an idiot!
코지로 개새끼!
You coward!
이 비겁자!
One more word and I'm not saving you.
더 말하면 안 살려준다.
Kojirō! When did you...
코지로! 어느 순간에...
I changed my clothes in the smoke. Even if it's you, I would miss you should you cease to be.
연기 속에서 갈아입었다. 너 같은 녀석이라도 없으면 허전하니 말이지.
Now! Let's run away!
자! 달아나자!
Escape success! Let's hurry and get out of this mansion-dasu!
탈출 성공! 빨리 이 집에서 나가오!
Idiot. When there are enemies everywhere, my sword alone isn't enough.
멍청하긴. 적이 있는 곳에서는 내 칼만으로는 무리다.
We must find your sword too!
네 칼도 찾아야 한다!
What is this?
뭣이오, 이건?
A fake sliding screen.
가짜 맹장지다.
My kotetsu!
내 코테츠!
Strange... There are no sign of chasers.
묘하군... 추적자의 기미가 없다.
Hanzō must have fallen asleep, not realizing that we escaped-dasu.
분명 한조 놈이 그새 자버린 바람에 깨닫지 못하는 것일 테오.
I hope so, but let's hurry up for now.
그렇다면 괜찮겠지만... 어쨌든 서두르자!
Idiots. You shall not simply run away.
멍청한 놈. 그저 달아나게 두었다 생각하나.
When I get to know where the secret message is, I'll kill you slowly.
밀서의 소재를 알게 될 쯤에 천천히 죽여 주겠다.
What? Are you saying that you're going to deliver that secret message to Jūbee in Edotopia?
뭐? 그 밀서, 에도토피아의 주베 님께 전달한다고?
Right. An atrocious villain like Hanzō is unforgivable-dasu!
그렇소. 한조같은 극악한 자는 용서할 수 없소!
But still...
그래도 말이지,
Hey, stop!
아, 잠깐!
Good.
좋소.
With this, Hanzō's gang will meet its end-dasu!
이것으로 한조 일당도 끝장이오!
Hey! Stop!
아! 멈추시오!
You- you must be...!
너, 너는!
It's ours now. Go!
잘 받았다. 가라!
Damn, they are too quick-dasu!
젠장, 너무 재빠르오!
Those guys followed us!
녀석들, 우리를 쫒아왔어!
They took the message-dasu!
밀서를 빼앗겼소!
Forget it! I refuse to be involved more than this!
내버려둬라! 이 이상 둘러싸이는 것은 사양이다!
Even if you say so...
그런 말을 해도!
We did it-dasu.
해냈소.
What should we do-dasu?
어쩌면 좋소?
Like I know! We just run!
딱히 방법이 있을까보냐! 별 방법이 없다!
This is it-dasu.
이것이오.
I'll finish you!
끝장이다!
Musashi!
무사시!
Take it back-dasu!
돌려주겠소!
You damned brats...
이 애송이들이...
I will have revenge on you!
이 원한은 꼭 갚아주겠다!
Thinking to use your enemy's weapon in a nick of time is praiseworthy even for you.
즉각적으로 적의 무기를 이용하는 것은 너 치고는 훌륭했다.
Then let's separate from now on.
그럼, 다시 갈라질까.
You still have a match against me-dasu.
나하고의 승부가 남아있소.
You know, with you, nothing goes alright.
너하고 같이 있으면 제대로 되는 게 없으니 말이지.
And also, I also have some convenient stuff.
게다가, 나도 이런 편리한 것을 가지고 있다.
Farewell!
안녕이다!
Idiot.
바보 놈.
That was cowardly-dasu!
비겁하오!
Damn you, Kojirō!
젠장, 코지로!
Huh, I'm too hungry to stand up straight-dasu...
어라, 배가 고파서 똑바로 설 수가 없소...
In this way, he managed to evade the evil hands of Hanzō, but he lost the secret message revealing his fearsome plot.
이렇게, 한조의 마의 손은 피해갔지만 그 무서운 음모를 밝히는 밀서를 잃어버렸다.
He was too tired and hungry. A starved swordsman still has high spirits, but Musashi wasn't quite there yet.
배가 고파 힘이 들어, 무사는 먹지 않아도 긍지많은 높다지만 갈 길은 먼 무사시였다.
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
I've ate and drink as much as I wanted-dasu. Moreover, because I could earn money,
마음껏 먹고 마셨소. 게다가 용돈까지 벌 수 있어서
I decided to help Katsuzō family-dasu,
나, 카츠조 일가를 돕게 되었소만,
but as everyone says, there's no such thing as a free lunch-dasu.
역시 공짜보다 비싼 것은 없다고 다들 그러오.
A twist of fate? I have to fight against Jirochiō family where Ishimatsu, who promised with me to be brothers, is in-dasu.
이 무슨, 형제의 약속을 맺은 이시마츠 씨가 있는 지로치오 일가하고 싸우게 되고 말았소.
Next story! A Man Ishimatsu, Friendship Falls-dasu.
다음 이야기! 사내 이시마츠, 우정이 지다
Cry by the stormy friendship-dasu!
질풍노도의 우정으로 우시오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
A Man Ishimatsu
사내 이시마츠
Friendship Falls
우정이 떨어지오
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!